Richard Price Papers 1767-1790 Mss.B.P93 Mss.B.P93
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Richard Price], March 14, 1786; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Naples, A.L.S. 3p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) News of his travels in France and Italy.
  - Letter to Richard Price, Newington-green, March, 1786; Lathrop, John, 1772-1820
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letter from...B.Franklin.) Concerning two young Englishmen. Concerning financial status of America. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser. 2, vol. 7, 336-337.
  - Letter to Richard Price, London, April 2, 1786; Bowdoin, James, 1752-1811
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. and add. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Sends volume of Memoirs of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Printed: Mass Hist.Soc. Proceedings. Ser. 2, vol. 7, 338.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, April 6, 1786; Willard, Joseph, 1738-1804
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. End. in shorthand. Enc. wanting. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concern over finances of the U.S. Sends copy of Memoirs of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser.2, vol.7, 338-339.
  - Letter to Richard Price, Newington Green, April 9, 1786; Eliot, Samuel
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. and add. End. Seal. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Friendly letter. Thanks him for his pamphlet.
  - Letter to Richard Price, April 22, 1786; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to Richard Price, London, May 25, 1786; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 7p. and add. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Printed: Butterfield, Letters of B.Rush, I, 388-390.
  - Letter to [Richard Price], June 22, 1786; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Constantinople, A.L.S. 4p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Studied prisons in the Mediterranean. Sights of the plague in Constantinople.
  - Letter to Richard Price, London, July 18, 1786; Clarke, John
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. and add. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Friendly letter. News of Charles Chauncy. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser. 2, vol. 7, 345.
  - Letter to Richard Price, London, July 27, 1786; Wigglesworth, Edward, 1732-1794
    Cambridge, Massachusetts, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from ...B.Franklin.) Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. Ser. 2, vol. 7, 345-346.
  - Letter to Richard Price, July 29, 1786; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to [Richard Price], July 29, 1786; Willard, Joseph, 1738-1804
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 3p. End. in shorthand. Enc. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings Ser. 2, vol. 7, 347-348.
  - Letter to [Richard Price], Aug. 2, 1786; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. End. in shorthand. Enc. wanting. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. Ser. 2, vol. 7, 349.
  - Letter to Joseph Willard, Oct. 6, 1786; Wigglesworth, Edward, 1732-1794
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 7p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning the granting of annuities to the widows of ministers with tables drawn up to probable death rates.
  - Letter to [Richard Price], Oct. 13, 1786; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Venice Lazaretto, A.L.S. 3p. End. (see Richard Price papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning his voyage from Smyrna to Venice. Bad news from England.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, Oct. 16, 1786; Sullivan, James, 1744-1808
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. End. in shorthand. (see Richard price Papers. Letters from... B.Franklin.) Concerning internal difficulties of Massachusetts. Sends Memoirs of American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser. 2, vol. 7, 352.
  - Letter to Richard Price, Oct. 25, 1786; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Vienna Lazaretto, A.L.S. 4p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning his distaste for a public memorial. Plans for the future.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, Oct. 27, 1786; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 7p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. Ser. 2, vol. 7, 352-354.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, London, Nov. 4, 1786; Vaughan, Samuel, 1720-1802
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price papers. Letters from.. .B.Franklin) Concerning public affairs of Penna. and the U.S. B.Franklin's health and activities. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceeding. ser. 2, vol. 7, 354-356.
  - Letter to [Richard Price], Dec. 1, 1786; Bingham, William, 1752-1804
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning the state of the U.S. and Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, London, Dec. 14, 1786; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Vienna, A.L.S. 1p. and add. End. Enc. (see Richard Price papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning his family and religion. Route of his trip to London. Also on same sheet is copy of letter from John Howard to Committee for... Prisons; Dec.15, 1786.
  - Letter to the Committee for Relieving Prisoners and reforming Prisons, Dec. 15, 1786; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Vienna, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. Copy. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Begs that no monument be raised to him. On same sheet with letter from John Howard to Richard Price; Dec. 14, 1786.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, London, Jan. 18, 1787; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Amsterdam, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Seal. Travel from Vienna. Hopes his statue is destroyed. Mentions Ingenhausz.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, London, April 2, 1787; Ingenhousz, Jan, 1730-1799
    Vienna, A.L.S. 1p. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from ...B. Franklin.) Annuities. Resumé of past events. Mentions Dr. Franklin.
  - Letter to [Richard Price], April 6, 1787; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. End. Enc. wanting. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from ...B.Franklin.) Sends pamphlet. Mentions B.Franklin. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser. 2, vol. 7, 336.
  - Letter to Richard Price, May 18, 1787; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to [Richard Price], June 2, 1787; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia. A.L.S. 5p. Enc. wanting. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Printed: Butterfield, Letters of B.Rush, I, 418-420.
  - Letter to Richard Price, June 9, 1787; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, London, July 25, 1787; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Belfast, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from ...B.Franklin.) Concerning prisons of Ireland.
  - Letter to Rich[ar]d Price, London, July 29, 1787; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. in shorthand. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from ...B.Franklin.) Introduces Mr. Winchester and speaks of him. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser. 2, vol. 7, 369-370.
  - Letter to Richard Price, London, July 31, 1787; White, William, 1748-1836
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from ...B.Franklin.) Introduces Joseph Workman. Discusses the constitutional convention. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser. 2, vol.7, 370.
  - Letter to [Richard Price], March 23 [?], 1788; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Dublin, A.L.S. 3p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning investigation of schools.
  - Letter to Richard Price, Nov. 19, 1788; Willard, Joseph, 1738-1804
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 3p. End. in shorthand. Enc. wanting. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. Ser. 2, vol. 7, 371-372.
  - Letter to [Richard Price], Dec. 22, 1788; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Warrington, A.L.S. 3p. End. in shorthand. Mutilated. Enc. wanting. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Is preparing a new volume on lazarettos.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, Jan. 8, 1789; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, A.L.S. 7p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from... B.Franklin.) Printed: Washington, Writings of T. Jefferson, II, 553-557.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, London, May 19, 1789; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B. Franklin.) Printed: Washington, Writings of T. Jefferson, III, 41-43.
  - Will, May 25, 1789; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    A.D.S. 4p. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.)
  - Letter to Richard Price, May 31, 1789; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    A.L.S. 2p. Discusses the "good bishop's" death; views on death; sends copies of Transactions.
  - Letter to Mathon de La Cour, July 1, 1789; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    Paris, Hackney, A.L. in 3d.P. 1p. and add. End. (see Richard Price Papers.) Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning beliefs on freedom.
  - Letter to Richard Price, Sept. 22, 1789; Howard, John, 1726-1790
    Moscow, A.L.S. 2p. End. Mutilated. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning his trip to Moscow and from there to Turkey.
  - Letter to Richard Price, London, April 24, 1790; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add. End. (see Richard Price Papers.) Letters from...B.Franklin.) Printed: Butterfield, Letters of B.Rush, I, 563-565.
  - Letter to ----, 1790; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    [ca.]. A.L. 4p. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Celebrated 14th of July. Mentions B.Franklin. Discusses Adam Smith. Printed: Mass.Hist.Soc. Proceedings. ser. 2, vol.17, 376-378.
  - Biographical account of John Howard., Undated; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    A.D. 9p. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Contains two printed obituaries.
  - Memorandum, Undated; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    A.D. 2p. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) ----Copy. 1p. End. Concerning events in England leading to the American revolution. [1775?]
  - Memorandum., Undated; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    A.D. 1p. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Concerning messages to friends. Mentions B.Franklin. Concerning Hessians and Hanoverians hired to fight.
  - Memorandum., Undated; Price, Richard, 1723-1791
    A.D. 3p. End. (see Richard Price Papers. Letters from...B.Franklin.) Story of Mr. Hutton, friend of B. Franklin being used by the king of England to make a better peace. For further information re: Hutton, see; Franklin Papers, vol.39,no.44.
  - Misellaneous letters, Undated
    A.L., A.D.S. and Ams. 5 items. This folder contains four papers written by Price (2 identical and one written in cipher), an account of houses in Ireland, and a resolution to the Court of the City (May Sambridge).